what makes a world-class sales
presentation and before you think about
I'm talking about door-to-door sales or
slimy sleazy tactics I'm talking about
something that people actually want to
listen to that turns into results for
your business if you're a coach Mentor
or trainer and you're not getting sales
or getting clients then you don't have a
business on today's video I want to walk
you through the process and tactics that
you can easily apply right away to see
results in your business for those of
you that I haven't met yet my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and for the last 21
years I've scaled multiple coaching and
course businesses to over $20 million a
year and what I do now is every single
week I work with beginner coaches and
mentors on how to scale their business
inside of my client growth accelerator
program we work with you come alongside
you become a part of your team to be
able to get you those results we have
people every single week making
Milestones making tens of thousands of
dollars in their businesses and that's
what I love helping people do is how to
go from struggling or just starting to
actually getting those clients and so
learning how to sell and how to
communicate in sales is that big part of
the process here's the thing when it
comes to selling people feel very
emotional both you as the salesperson
and as the Prospect and we have a stigma
around the word sales we think of the
used car salesman that nobody wants to
be like first off I want to say this I
don't want to be like that myself and I
don't teach anybody to be that way when
I teach people how to to do is how to
show up in their best energy
authentically and then how to turn that
into a sales conversation the best way
to get sales is by making a connection
with people duh of course but how do we
do that through the internet right by
video content when you can learn how to
deliver video sales presentations in an
effective way you can close more sales
and so I want to break down for you is
the process the tactics and the the
blueprint for what to say and how to say
it in your video presentations there's a
number of different formats that people
do for video presentations whether it be
webinars or challenges or what we call
vsls even YouTube videos have an element
of this to them though I don't use my
YouTube videos in any way to sell people
I use these more to make a connection
and to deepen the trust that we have
overall I know that not everybody who
watches my YouTube videos is going to
become a client but I know that some
will and we hear frequently from our
paid clients they decided to become our
client because they watch a lot of our
YouTube videos that's why I keep making
them either way if you want to get more
sales you got to learn how to deliver
worldclass presentations and the number
one thing to do is to not bore people to
death often times people are just bored
and they know you're trying to sell them
something and so what you got to do is
you got to learn how to completely turn
that on its head and show up in a way
that people actually want to listen to
you know when people go to a movie
remember there's a difference between a
good movie and a bad movie you ever been
to a a really crappy movie and you're
like gosh I wish I got my money back
from this the trailer was great but then
the movie was terrible unfortunately
that's what ends up happening when you
don't know how to deliver a good sales
presentation is that people don't enjoy
listening to it and so you want it to be
enjoyable it needs to be entertaining
and informing and connect emotionally
and the way that we do that is we really
get into what drives somebody to make
that decision to buy from us people
purchase on emotion and feeling more
than anything else now you might be
watching this saying Jeremiah I don't
purchase on emotion and feeling I
purchase on logic and truth I hear that
from everybody they all think that
that's what we think we buy on but
here's the reality is that we only
purchase something or even have an
interest in it if we feel good about it
and when it comes to your coaching
business when it comes to hiring a coach
the only reason that somebody actually
hires you as a coach is because they
feel really good about working with you
and it's not necessarily that you're
pleasing them or that you're saying
paying all the right things to get them
to buy from you but it's that they like
the vibe and they like the energy so the
first tactic when it comes to your sales
is getting that Vibe and energy right
it's not a woowoo term it's like you
actually show up as somebody that
believes in themselves that is enjoyable
to listen to and that people like they'd
love to spend more time with you when it
comes to coaching when it comes to
online courses people are going to spend
a lot of time with you virtually and
digitally and possibly even in person
and so what you're doing is you're
demonstrating to them that this is going
to be a great time that we're going to
have a great time together and whenever
I make sales presentations I want it to
have that in it I show up with
excitement my body language is excited
I'm happy I get rid of all of the
distractions in my mind and that's one
of the other things to do is to really
get focused on that you're talking to
the right group of people one of the
other tactics that we love to do
whenever it comes to do doing sales
presentations is expect that the person
that you're talking to is qualified
already that they're the right person
now we understand that not everybody's
going to be qualified for our offers in
fact the data shows that whenever we do
a presentation that only about 5% of the
people who even sign up for a
presentation let's say it's a lead
Magnet or it's a free webinar are even
going to become any level of a client or
purchase with us and if people purchase
a course or something from us that bumps
up to about 25% and that's great and
those numbers are much better better
there but even then the majority of the
people are not going to become your
client it's kind of like baseball
players you know baseball players
actually miss a good baseball player
misses 70% of every pitch that's thrown
to them did you know that a good
basketball player misses about 40% 50%
of every shot they
take in in sports that's that's the
analogy and and so when it comes to
sales and marketing there is a number
game access to it you could do all the
right things you could say all the right
things and yet most everybody that you
even do a presentation to is never going
to buy from you and so understand that
that's not a bad thing that that's just
reality that's how things are and then
go to work by expecting that who you're
talking to is already qualified and is
the right person then we go into the
tactics of what do we actually talk
about how do we actually deliver that
presentation so there's a three-step
structure that we use when we're doing
presentations like like this and the
structure goes like this number one you
want to start with casting
vision for where you're going and what
this means is that we're going to do the
three right there
that the place that you're taking them
in the presentation whenever somebody
comes into a sales presentation with you
it is a
journey it's not a Sprint it's a
marathon and it might feel like that for
you especially if you're just starting
out is that when you deliver a sales
presentation of some kind that we start
off by pulling people into our
environment and we create the right
environment and set the stage for what
is going to feel really good for people
so what we do whenever we do any kind of
sales presentation is we show people in
their mind we cast Vision so they can
see internally in their Mind's Eye the
direction that we're going on that
Journey whatever that outcome is I want
you to look at the finish line that
you're taking somebody to not just when
they buy from you but after they buy
from you what is that vision for their
life that they're going to have and you
want to help them to reinforce that
because when you can reinforce belief in
somebody that they are able to do it
that they are able to experience it that
it's going to be fun that it's going to
be enjoyable you have somebody hooked
and you can communicate with them now
the first six minutes of any kind of
presentation that's where the highest
level of Engagement comes if you can
keep somebody engaged for about 6
minutes you can talk about anything with
them and so that's really one of the
most important parts of it and the first
minute is where somebody's really like
getting a feel for your energy and how
you feel and what you're talking about
and so understand that you got to show
up at the highest level with that you
got to have excitement you got to have
urgency you got to have a sense of
self-belief you got to show and
demonstrate that you're safe and that's
one of the other things and when it
comes to sales when it comes to getting
people to buy from you is to demonstrate
that you are a safe person for people to
listen to I'm going to talk about that a
little bit at the end of this video
about safety and how we can take people
through that but the way that we bring
this around is we start by talking about
the vision of what is going to happen so
we already know that they are coming in
for something that we promis some kind
of an outcome in a sales presentation
and maybe you're wondering that how do
we actually get people to listen to a
sales presentation again in a lot of my
videos I talk about that about lead
generation about marketing you want to
figure out what is the desire that
somebody has that they want to listen to
and we want to separate these two
because before somebody actually comes
into a presentation that's all marketing
and advertising and so marketing and
advertising is about getting somebody
into a sales presentation once you do
the presentation this is a different
game all together where you're actually
selling to people and there's a process
to this so we figure out what do they
desire the most what do they want what
is that desired outcome and we promise
that to somebody by going through this
now in the first 33% of the presentation
we're going to be talking
about how that is going to look for them
we're not going to be going over tactics
we're not going to be going over how to
do the process we're not going to be
talking about our Frameworks one of the
biggest mistakes that I see from coaches
who are amazing mentors amazing coaches
but they struggle to get sales is
they're way too focus on their tactics
their Frameworks and how they do things
and they're trying to get people to
understand how to bring transformation
when they haven't made a connection yet
and they haven't made that emotional
connection so the emotional connection
happens in this beginning portion where
you're bringing Vision into the table
now here's the truth in this portion
you're also going to lose some people
because they don't want this they're
impatient they're not the right person
for you they're not qualified and
anybody who drops off at this stage of
your presentation was never going to do
anything in the P first in in the first
place no matter what you said no matter
what you did no matter how you
structured it and we've tested this
across the board with hundreds of
presentations we tried it where we bring
in the tactics in the beginning the same
and in fact less
people engag and are even more
disappointed when we do that and so the
truth is is get rid of out of your mind
the fear and worry about disappointing
other people stop trying to
control that aspect of the outcome and
just assume assume that you're talking
to somebody who loves you who thinks
that you're amazing that wants to just
hang out with you and spend the most
amount of time with you I imagine that
I'm talking to my best clients I have
clients they want to listen to
everything that I talk about and they
love everything we talk about and they
are getting results in their business
and they're leaning in and they're
leaning forward and they are producing
results and then I got the kind of
skeptical I call them on the outside and
and listen if that's you again no hate I
understand I used to be that way a lot
you're listening to me you're you're
watching this but those people are not
the ones who are actually going to buy
from you so you imagine that you're
speaking to somebody who just loves
everything that comes out of your mouth
whenever I make a video presentation
even whenever I make YouTube content I
just imagine that I'm talking to
somebody that I love talking to that
trusts what I'm talking about they want
to hear it and they're not going to be
upset or disappointed if maybe I stutter
or I say something off or I I I lose my
train of thought or anything like that
what that does is it allows me to
actually get out of my head out of that
protective State of Mind out of worrying
about what people are going to think
about me and able to show up to serve
people and the way that we serve people
is by making that connection for the
future that somebody's going to
experience so we show them what that
future is that they're going to
experience in our words in our
communication through our storytelling
by walking people through a process
verbally to where we can paint a picture
in their mind of what they are going to
experience we cast vision for that we
also talk about the mindset that is
needed if we're going to go into
anything practically in this section
it's going to be about mindset the
mental state of mind that people need to
be in inside of the presentation to be
able to get the most result now we go
into the middle portion and this is what
we call practicality but before we get
here one of the things that we want to
do is that we want to mention whatever
it is that we have for sale just like
what we have my client growth
accelerator program where I work with
coaches mentors trainers to be able to
get the most amount of clients in their
business and to close the most amount of
sales you can get on the waiting list
for that you can also check out the free
training that we have below we have a
free class that we put together for you
that's going to help you be able to get
more clients and grow your business fast
and again what I just did was I
mentioned something that I am promoting
in this video right here I even just
gave you an example of that and how you
do that and how you can segue in and do
a slight commercial so right around the
12 minute Mark you notice we're about 13
and a half minutes in right around the
12 minute Mark of your presentation you
do a
soft mention of whatever it is that
you're going to sell as well at the
beginning and some of y'all didn't catch
this at the beginning of this video I
actually talked about what we have to
offer my accelerator program I talked
about how we work with our clients and
what we do with them every single week
to get those results and so in that
you're already only 33% through the
presentation and you're making a
connection with somebody where they know
that you have something for sale now
it's not bait and switch now you're not
they're not anticipating well what what
are they trying to sell me at the end of
this they already know you have
something to offer and you're not being
dishonest you're not being somebody
who's trying to disguise your intentions
so that's really cool is that you can if
you can show up and actually be honest
and have integrity to show people what
it is and how you're going to help them
then what you're able to do is you're
able to mention that in the beginning
portion of this presentation so whenever
you're doing a video presentation of any
kind in that beginning portion we got
Vision we got mindset we mention what
we're going to sell at the very
beginning within like the first minute
or two and we do another soft mention of
it right around 12 minutes in then what
we do is we go into this practicality
part of it remember I mentioned what is
the desired outcome that somebody has
what is that desired goal that they have
that they want to to accomplish that
they want to achieve what is that thing
that they want to get out of working
with us whatever you did to get somebody
into this presentation whatever
marketing whatever advertising you used
you got to have some kind of a hook
that's going to promise an outcome to
people that you're promising to walk
them through some kind of a process to
get to an outcome and so in the middle
of our sales presentation is where we
can actually deliver that portion of it
right in the middle of it we talk about
the tactics we talk about the howto we
talk about the process because now this
portion right here this is maybe going
to be about 33% of the presentation as
well so we got 33% 33% let's say it's an
hourong presentation this might look
like the first 20 minutes this is going
to look like the second the second 20
minutes 20 to 40 minutes and then the
last part right here is the final 33%
which is you know 40 to 60 Minutes long
and so in this part you're going to
deliver what you promised in the
beginning part of it
in what you brought them into you're
going to actually give them the secret
sauce of whatever that is and what you
want to do here is you want to deliver
something that is extremely valuable
something that people would pay a lot of
money for something that you've charged
a lot of money for one of the biggest
mistakes that I see that mentors and
coaches make is that they hold back in
this portion here's the cool part about
it the reason why we have the vision and
mindset part right here is we are
qualifying and actually I'll say this is
that we are making sure that the ones
who get those practical Parts they are
going to have to sit through an initial
portion of this where they get to prove
to us that they are worthy to listen to
this part of it without paying for it
because if you're giving it away for
free you want to make sure that you're
giving it to the right people and when
the right people hear the the vision and
mindset and then you give the Practical
Frameworks you give the highest value of
what you have to offer what you would
charge money for in this part right here
and and by the it's whatever you can
deliver in 20 minutes I can't give you
my whole framework for my business in 20
minutes but I can give you one or two
pieces I right now in this video I'm
literally doing that with you I'm giving
you a blueprint for what you can do to
get more clients in your business in my
accelerator program I show you how to
attract those people to you we have
tactics and strategies to walk you
through what to say how to say it
scripts that you can follow to know
exactly what to get what to go through
to get those clients to convert and then
how to close more sales in your business
so in this middle portion right here
that's where you go through that aspect
of it is where you deliver high value
this is where you deliver your content
portion of it whatever you're going to
be teaching and you don't want to over
te what I recommend is do like a bird's
eye view imagine a checklist like you're
going down a checklist of ideas and one
of the things that we can do is we can
even use artificial intelligence to help
us map a lot of this out right here
which is really awesome that's one of
the things that I enjoy doing is using
AI to help me come up with how am I
going to break this down what are those
steps that I'm going to take I take some
of my transcripts from our sessions with
our clients I bring that into the AI and
I have it break it down that way for me
these are some of the things that we
teach you inside my accelerator program
is how to do this how to use AI to be
able to automate a lot of these steps in
your process and I'd love to see you in
there and working with us again now you
might notice even in this video I'm
talking a lot about my accelerator
program and you want to do that in any
sort of sales presentation is that no
matter what you're selling no matter
what that thing is you want to find a
way to bring it all back to that you
want to bring it all back to the thing
that you are selling so even though
you're delivering value even though
you're walking people through a process
even though you're showing them
something that is extremely valuable
that is worth a ton to them you're
looping it back to the part where you're
going to cell which is in the last
portion here of this and this is where
you go all in with your sales
presentation one of the things that you
want to have is you want to have on your
website the best way to close your sales
through video is to have some kind of a
page where you can take people and walk
them through the thing that you are
selling them on such as right now we
have a free class right here again you
can see this it might if you're watching
this video later you might find that we
have a different class that we're
hosting but this is the current free
class that we're hosting right now where
we walk you through how to use Facebook
ads to get more clients we're going to
be launching a new class here soon about
how to start your business all that to
say is that you want to have a page
developed where you can walk people
through and down this process so this is
what we call a landing page I have a
number of different videos on my YouTube
channel all about creating landing pages
that you can go through and on this what
I'm going to do is I'm going to read
through this with them while they're on
the presentation I'm going to walk them
through step by step everything that is
written on this page and what that does
is it allows us to be able to show them
not just send them a link not just say
hey go check the link out later but I'm
able to actually guide and direct them
through the purchasing process and I get
really confident I stay confident I stay
excited and I expect that anybody who's
still watching me right here and by the
way you're going to have a drop off of
people if you have let's say 100 people
who start watching your presentation by
the end here you're only going to have
about 50 that are watching at this point
you're going to have a drop off of
people that stopped
watching and so this 50 who stays into
this part right here if they continue
watching through that sales pitch
portion right there they want to hear
that and so this is one of the things to
do is to assume that anybody who's still
listening to you selling wants to hear a
sales pitch and so don't hold back don't
hold back your energy really start to
deliver start to talk about what the
benefits are why they should jump in get
very direct with the fact that it's one
of the best things that they're going to
experience that they can go through and
it's going to get them results and if
you do this if you're able to walk
people through this process then you are
able to close more sales and one of the
best ways that we do this is that we
walk people through a process that we
call four pillars three Transformations
and one big outcome and so the way that
that is is that on a piece of paper we
show people what are the four pillars of
what we are selling them if we're a
coach if we're a mentor if we're a
course creator what are the three main
problems that we solve and
Transformations that we bring in their
life then what is one big outcome and so
the way that we draw this is I'll draw
this on the Whiteboard or I'll have a
Graphic that I'll actually walk people
through this on screen right here so the
graphic looks something a little bit
like this okay so like for my
accelerator program this is exactly what
we walk people through and in my
presentation I actually pull this
graphic up on screen to show people this
to walk them through these different
stages of what it is like to work with
us I help people find their Niche if
they don't know what it is how to write
their sales copy how to optimize their
content ads and funnels and master sales
skills this is how we take people from
Total beginner to being able to close
six and even seven figures in sales we
take them from and then so those are the
four pillars what we teach and then you
can see the triangle right here what is
a around the triangle the three
Transformations from complicated
messaging to persuasive messaging we're
transforming their process into that
we're transforming their life from low
impact to massive impact we're
transforming their experience from
sporadic income to consistent cash flow
okay whatever business you're in
whatever coaching business you're in you
can fit in your business an outline of
this and actually structure this to
whatever it is that you're doing
and then financial and time freedom and
that's in the middle triangle right
there because that's the ultimate
outcome that people are going to
experience that we're taking people into
because that's the real want and the
real desire that people have the only
reason why people build funnels the only
reason why we're coaching is we want to
have impact cash flow we want to dial in
that messaging but it's really
truthfully not just for those reasons
but it's so that we can have financial
and time freedom in our life and have
the kind of impact that we want to have
to be able to help people and to really
live a life that we enjoy for our
families and to change our future
together and so in my accelerator
program that's exactly what we work with
you through that's exactly the process
that we walk with you through and that's
exactly what you want to do when you're
selling in your business is that you
want to come up with your version of
this where you're going to write out
these four pillars we're you you're
going to talk about what is pillar
number one like I said finding your
Niche what is pillar number two the
sales copy pillar number three we're
going to optimize your campaigns what is
pillar number four we're going to help
you sell so that you can have and we
draw that triangle right there so you
can have the the messaging the impact
and the income so that you have
financial and time freedom I and I kind
of scribbled that out really quickly but
that's really what it is so what it does
is it draws them inward towards this
real existential idea and goal and
desire and dream that they have so you
can deliver all of this information all
these Transformations all that stuff
like that but this is really what's
going to close people as a sale is
they're going to be able to really get a
vision for how it's going to work with
you you're you're going to solve these
these issues you're going to help create
these transformations in their life and
you're going to actually help them build
a new life and a new version of
themselves that's going to be able to
get everything they want and experience
the kind of results that you promise in
your offer so when when you're selling
you got to have some kind of an
irresistible offer this is a great way
to have structure to that irresistible
offer to be able to express it with
people and by the way this is something
that we have we found almost by accident
but we discover this cuz I noticed a
number of different people were doing
presentations that we were looking at
and and oh by the way here's another
tactic for sales go watch other people's
sales presentations pay attention to
their energy one of the things you can
do is on Facebook or Instagram you can
actually click on advertisements from
other coaches and mentor mentors and you
can go through and look at how they
present and how they sell in their
business I purchased two courses this
week from two essentially competitors of
mine because I wanted to see just one or
two of the nuances of how they would be
closing the sale in their process and I
was like okay and I learned Mass it was
worth the investment I spent I spent
about $70 and it was worth the
investment to figure out in about an
hour exactly what that Nuance was that I
was able to then borrow and we can
bolt-on in my business and so that's one
of the best ways to discover how to show
up how to communicate and how to sell is
to look at other people's that are
successful their sales presentations if
you see somebody who's got success
online and you see them delivering a
presentation you might say well how do I
know if they're delivering a
presentation let me tell you this if
anybody is giving you content that's
free at the end of the day there's
something that they're selling or
offering in it okay and and that's okay
that's not a bad thing that's by Design
but if you do it well and if you do it
properly you're going to be able to give
tactical knowledge tactical advice and
be able to deliver those results to
people you might notice again in this
video I was actually pretty much selling
you on working with me in my accelerator
program this alone was a sales pitch in
and of itself but I was able to bring it
all together to show you how to
communicate in a way that is effective
and it actually works and I gave you a
lot of tactics and a lot of strategies
that you can do now again I'd love to
see you on one of my live classes I'd
love to see you in my program and I'd
love to work with you to help you get
results so that you don't have to
struggle in your business so you can
start to get more coaching clients
course clients Consulting clients
whatever that is in your business as
well I'll talk soon have a good one make
sure to
subscribe and I'll see you next time